Elizabeth Stephens Papers, 1921-1926
Smith College Archives
Elizabeth Stephens Papers
1921-1926
Stephens, Elizabeth, 1902-
RG 80. Class of 1924.
5 boxes (1.35 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
Smith graduate. Contains correspondence, class notes, photgraphs, and academic work.
Elizabeth Stephens was born on March 10, 1902 in Montclair, New Jersey to Thomas Wilcox Stephens, a manufacturer, and Elizabeth (Henderson) Stephens. Prior to her enrollment at Smith College in 1920, Stephens attended The Shipley School (Bryn Mawr, PA), Miss Walker's School (Simsbury, Connecticut), and Milton Academy (Milton, Massachusetts). Stephens graduated from Smith College on June 19, 1924 with an AB and married Ogden Bigelow in 1926. Ogden Junior was born in 1928 and their daughter, Ann (AB '51), in 1929.
The Elizabeth Stephens Papers are primarily related to her years spent at Smith College, dating from 1921 to 1926. Types of material include correspondence; class notes; photographs; and academic work.
The majority of this collection is comprised of correspondence. Included are exchanges with Stephens' future husband, Ogden Bigelow and letters from both the Stephens and the Bigelow families pertaining to the wedding.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
Ann B. Hamilton donated the letters of Elizabeth Stephens to the College Archives in April 1999. Other papers were donated to the College Archives over a period of years.
Search Terms
Stephens, Elizabeth, 1902-; Smith College--Students.
Additional Information
Related Material
80. Class of 1924 Records
- Correspondence 1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence JAN-FEB 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence MAR-APR 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence MAY 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence JUN-JUL 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence AUG 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence SEP 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence OCT 1923 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence NOV 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence DEC 1923 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence JAN 1924 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence FEB 1924 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence MAR 1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence APR 1924 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence MAY 1924 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence JUN 1924 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence JUL 1924 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence AUG 1-AUG 17, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence AUG 18-AUG 29, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence SEP-DEC 1924 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence JAN-JUN, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence JUL 1-JUL 23, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence AUG 1-AUG 7, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence AUG 8-AUG 14, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence AUG 15-AUG 22, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence AUG 24-AUG 31, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence SEP-DEC 1925 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence JAN 30-AUG 30, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Class Notes Art 22: Introduction to the History of Art 1922-23 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Class Notes Art 22: General History of Art 1922-23 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Class Notes Art 310: The Development of House Furniture 1923-24 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Class Notes Geology II: General Geology 1922-23 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Class Notes Sociology 37a: Population and Vital Statistics 1923-24 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings (c/o Ogden Bigelow) 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Paper "The Essence of Confucianism as Taught by its Founder" undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Paper "The Place of Italy in the Development of Painting" undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Diary "A Line a Day" 1921-1924 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Photographs undated (Box 5, Folder 10)